♪ Pink hands so fine ♪
♪ Gold-branded wine ♪
♪ Spring paints willows green;
palace walls can't confine ♪
♪ East wind unfair ♪
♪ Happy times rare ♪
♪ In my heart, sad thoughts throng ♪
♪ We've severed for years long ♪
♪ Wrong, wrong, wrong ♪
Si Jin
Episode 19
(Open and Noble)
Do I have
to send Yi back to her maiden home?
Who said anything about that?
Sometimes,
I just get mad at you.
Why do you always take her side?
Son,
what's wrong with you today?
Before, whenever I asked you
to abandon her,
you'd fight me to the end.
Why did you
bring it up yourself today?
Aren't I just worried
that you might act on impulse
and actually send her back?
If you were only saying it in anger,
you should've told me sooner,
so I wouldn't be so worried.
If I told you,
I'm afraid
you'd run straight to Yi
and tell her everything.
Then she'd become even more defiant,
showing me
even less respect.
Fine, let's not mention that.
She's always
with her sister now.
Even our relationship
isn't as close as before.
She's just an unmarried girl.
One day,
she'll return
to Earl Dongping's Mansion.
She won't be here for long.
You should hurry and send someone
to find Qing'er.
Where has she gone?
Yes.
Miss Jiang.
It's you who saved me?
Just as you predicted,
Zhu Ziyu never intended
to keep his promise.
The moment he found me useless,
he wanted to kill me.
You saved my life.
I will surely repay this debt.
No need to be so formal.
Let her be formal.
We need your help with something.
Is Qing'er taken care of?
Yes.
I've ensured
that she vanished without a trace.
Young Master, where is my sister?
Please let her go.
Deliver a letter for me.
If you do as I say,
once the task is done,
not only will I let your sister go,
but I will also grant her freedom.
But if you can't even
handle such a small matter,
then consider
what might happen to her.
Very good.
Miss Yu'er.
Someone is waiting for you
in the carriage.
Yu'er.
Qing'er.
Yu'er, get in.
Qing'er, are you alright?
Zhu Ziyu has promised me.
Soon, he will set you free.
But why are you
with Miss Jiang?
Set me free?
In Zhu Ziyu's eyes,
I am already
a lifeless corpse.
Of course, I am free.
What do you mean?
Zhu Ziyu feared my betrayal
and tried to kill me.
Luckily, Miss Jiang and Mr. Yu
saved me despite our past grievances.
Otherwise, you and I
would've been separated by death.
Yu'er,
you seem to be in a hurry.
Are you going
to deliver a letter for Zhu Ziyu?
This...
It's alright, Yu'er.
Zhu Ziyu is not to be trusted.
Now, our only chance
is to help Miss Jiang.
Let's give the letter to her.
The plan has changed.
Await further instructions.
Wait.
Don't worry, Yu'er.
I have a way
to set you two free.
Miss,
Zhu Ziyu sent Qing'er again.
He said
he was waiting for you
in a hidden house.
He had something important to say
and asked me to take you there.
Mr. Zhu,
the letter has been delivered.
That lady said
she was waiting for you
in a hidden house
and asked me to bring you there.
She's too eager.
Mr. Zhu,
the lady is inside.
If it was just a rumor,
how could I have returned unharmed?
It's the abandoned house
on Carp Lane ahead.
A beauty awaits me.
Who are you trying to fool?
Has Mrs. Zhu Ziyu
lost her mind?
You don't believe me?
Seeing is believing.
I'll take you there myself.
It's just ahead.
We're almost there.
Let's go.
I miss you so much.
Give me more time.
I'll find a way
to abandon Jiang Yi.
No.
I'll kill Jiang Yi.
How much longer do I have to wait?
If this continues,
I might start to doubt
how true
your feelings for me are.
(Before, )
(to harm my sister, Cui Mingyue)
(had been spying on the Zhu family)
(but didn't collaborate with Zhu Ziyu.)
(To my surprise, )
(after all those changes, )
(they ended up conspiring together)
(to kill my sister.)
Heaven and earth can testify
to my feelings for you.
But her sister is quite troublesome,
and she has
a skilled Commandant by her side.
A Commandant?
It's Yu Qi from Capital Security.
Yu Qi?
He's come to Lingshui?
Do you know Yu Qi?
How would I know him?
Ziyu,
are you saying
as long as Jiang Si stays,
you won't be able to make a move?
She even ruined our meticulous plan
at Yunshui Tower.
I fear if we act recklessly,
we'll leave evidence behind.
Didn't Qing'er already reveal herself?
Why still use her to pass messages?
Don't worry.
Qing'er has been killed.
Since she's of no use,
it's better she's gone for good.
That's her twin sister, Yu'er.
They just look alike.
Once it's done,
they won't be alive.
What about Meng Nan
from Caiyun Troupe?
He said he'd stay by my side every day
to cheer me up.
How dare an actor
like him entertain such fantasies?
How dare a lowly man
like him stain your eyes?
He's good at drumming
and has a bit of charm.
He's kept around
for amusement.
After all,
you can't be with me every day.
I want to be with you day and night,
forever and always.
Your Grace, you promised me
you'd marry me, right?
You can never
look at other men again.
It's just ahead.
We're almost there.
Meng is a fool.
I had him spread rumors
about Jiang Yi,
and he actually did it.
I'm just afraid
he'll blurt out the truth
if he's arrested.
What truth?
Since the beginning,
he's never seen my true face.
You've never appeared either.
It was always Qing'er passing messages.
Are you scared?
As you wish.
- It's here.
Push the door open.
You've brought them here?
- Don't worry. I'm here.
- Open the door.
- Open the door!
We can't leave from both doors now.
There's even nowhere to hide.
You fool, we're trapped.
Let's go.
- Meng Nan.
- It's a man
meeting with Mr. Meng?
Aren't you blind?
Don't you see the woman behind him?
Oh.
Indeed.
Who are you?
This is my family's place.
Get lost now!
Darling, are you alright?
Don't leave yet.
Yi.
Was Ziyu calling for you just now?
- Yi.
- You're keeping a mistress secretly.
Now that you've been caught,
you're using my sister
as a shield?
Honey, I see. You love someone else.
Is it because of her
that you went to such lengths
to harm me?
Yi, it's a misunderstanding.
Don't listen
to your sister's instigation.
At this point,
how dare you say I'm instigating this?
A lone man and a woman
in a secret alley.
What misunderstanding could there be?
Explain yourself.
Let everyone judge.
Right.
Miss,
how long do you plan to hide?
You dared to meet with a married man,
but you lack the courage to admit it?
Let everyone see
whose daughter this is.
Jiang Si, how dare you.
Who could be as bold as you?
You know her?
Cui Mingyue.
How powerful the Grand Princess is.
You've kept the news so well.
Not long ago,
Cui Mingyue attempted
to kill my brother,
so she was demoted by His Majesty.
Now, she's even more resentful
toward our family.
Do you really think
the only daughter of the Grand Princess
would like you?
Which one do you trust, her or me?
It's up to you.
Let go.
Since you've seen
that Mingyue and I are in love,
let's part on good terms.
(It's her.)
(The Grand Princess.)
Mother.
Your Highness.
Mingyue and I are in love.
I hope you can approve.
Mother,
I was deceived by Zhu Ziyu.
When I first arrived here,
he showered me with sweet words
and was persistent and clingy.
Mother, please believe me.
Zhu Ziyu, be wise.
If you dare to pester her again,
I'll take your life.
Your Highness,
shielding the County Princess like this
is aiding evil.
How dare you!
The County Princess
disregards others' lives,
treating them like ants.
One day, this will lead
to a mistake that can't be undone.
Are you teaching me
how to discipline my daughter?
You know the best how His Majesty
dealt with the only son
of Marquis Changxing
when he made a mistake.
Jiang Si, you're bold.
The County Princess said
Zhu Ziyu deceived you
with sweet words,
but I think
this was a trap
you carefully set up
for my sister
to avenge your demotion.
You're sharp-tongued,
but I detest
being threatened.
Stop!
What are you trying to do?
You must be Yu Qi.
Is Lingshui also
under the control of Capital Security?
We're not like you
who can rule
and domineer over everyone
inside or outside Ling'an.
Yu Qi, how dare you
speak ill of the Grand Princess?
I wouldn't dare.
I can't ignore the law
like the County Princess.
Let me remind you.
His Majesty has had a verdict
on the Jinshui River Case.
Mingyue is merely a victim.
What happened today is already clear.
If you keep quiet,
I'll have no interest
in your lives.
(Since I can't avoid it, )
(I'll have to be ready for the battle.)
Yi, I was blind.
Please forgive me.
As you wish,
let's part ways.
(Zhu Mansion)
(Mr. Zhu)
You wretched child!
Bring the family punishment!
Today,
I must beat this son to death
to uphold our reputation.
- Honey.
- Don't interfere.
It's all your indulgence.
Yi,
don't worry.
I'll make sure this is resolved,
and justice will be served.
I only wish to part ways.
Yi, get up.
Yi,
my son Yu
has committed an unforgivable sin.
But, as you've not thought of yourself,
you should at least think of Yan.
After all, you're married.
What's so hard to overcome?
Yan...
Mr. Zhu,
if we're talking about justice,
this matter
should've been dealt with
at the court.
I...
It's because of Yan
that my sister would rather
discuss this privately.
With the current situation,
we must take Yan with us.
What right does an unmarried girl
like you have
to make decisions for your sister?
Yi,
I know
you won't be so cruel
to do this.
Right?
What will happen to a woman
like you with a daughter
after the divorce?
There's no need for you to worry.
Our family is declining,
but we can accommodate Yi.
Son,
kowtow and apologize to Yi,
and promise it won't happen again.
Yi,
I was vile and despicable.
I've betrayed you.
Yi,
please give me one more chance.
You tried to kill your wife
and committed adultery with a lady.
You're truly despicable.
Since my sister
has now seen
your true face,
how could she give you another chance
to continue your marriage?
Tried to kill his wife?
You can't make baseless accusations.
Mr. Zhu,
not long ago,
my sister almost lost her life
when a horse ran wild
on the road to Cloud Temple.
Have you investigated
the truth behind this?
Well...
I've long suspected
the mastermind behind that
was Zhu Ziyu.
At that time,
Commandant Yu was also there,
witnessing the whole incident.
Mr. Zhu,
have you thought this through?
If you don't agree to divorce,
we'll take accident
to the court.
If it turns out
to be related to Zhu Ziyu,
then you and your son's careers...
You'd better write
the Letter of Divorce now.
From now on,
my sister and your son
will part ways,
no longer involved in marriage,
death, or anything else.
Otherwise, we'll meet in court.
Since she wants a divorce,
let's grant her wish.
Didn't you always want
to get rid of her, Mother?
Today is just the right day.
And Yan
is just a girl.
She'll marry into another family.
If they want her,
let them take her.
We can't let this go to the court
and ruin my future.
You...
This...
♪ Life is like flowers,
blooming and fading with the seasons ♪
♪ Wind leaves marks,
swaying in the breeze ♪
♪ I don't wish for favors
from the heavens ♪
Yi...
♪ I only wish to be unburdened ♪
♪ Fate's been written; we're its slaves ♪
♪ I dare not look back
at the road I came from ♪
(Letter of Divorce)
♪ I only wish to wake up one day ♪
(Our daughter)
♪ Alas, is it too late
to stop indulging myself ♪
♪ Is it too difficult ♪
I, Zhu Ziyu, with my wife, Jiang,
think differently,
and it's hard to reconcile.
We seek a separation.
This document is written
to affirm our parting.
Our daughter
and boat of her dowry
will be with Jiang.
Our future marriages
won't be subject to disputes.
For future evidence,
I volunteer to write this contract.
Miss,
the rain has stopped,
and the sky is clear.
Qing'er, you go first.
If Zhu Ziyu catches you,
he won't let you go.
Yu'er, what will you do if I leave?
As long as you're well,
I'll be content.
My deed is still in his hands.
In this life,
I fear I'll be trapped here.
Give me Yu'er's deed.
What?
What Yu'er?
Continue.
Don't! I'll give it to you.
From now on,
if you dare to trouble them,
it'll be more than a beating.
Let's go.
Yu'er.
- Miss Si.
This is your deed.
From now on,
(Deed of Person)
you two
are free.
- Thank you, Miss Si.
- Get up.
Your Grace.
I knew it.
You were just afraid
of the Grand Princess
to admit it,
but you still have feelings
for me, right?
What a fool.
You really think I'd care for you?
But I've been sincere
to you, Your Grace.
You even tried
to kill your wife.
How can you be sincere?
I've seen plenty
of snobs like you.
A little benefit is enough
to entice you.
Unfortunately,
you failed to kill Jiang Yi.
But
watching your marriage fall apart,
and seeing how desperate Jiang Yi is,
I found it quite amusing.
You played me like a puppet
and caused my family to fall apart
just for amusement?
What else?
Life is long,
and I have everything I need.
Of course, I need something
to entertain myself.
Zhu Ziyu,
you've seen it.
People who offend me
never end well.
So,
just give me what I want,
or else,
a broken family is just the beginning.
If all your family is killed...
What do you think?
That's more like it.
(Fenglin Inn)
Aunt, which one
do you think is prettier?
I think these two are pretty.
Then let's have them stand together.
Aunt.
- Yan, wait.
- What do you think...
Eat this wonton first.
Sure.
What should you say at this moment?
Thank you, Brother.
I'm not your brother.
I'm about the same age
as your aunt,
so you should call me Uncle.
That's Aunt, and I'm Uncle.
Thank you, Uncle.
- Good girl.
Here.
Let me feed you.
Good.
Be careful. It's hot.
Take a sip of the soup.
Uncle is too busy looking at Aunt
to notice the wonton.
I didn't have time...
Alright, Yan.
Commandant Yu,
thank you for your help these days.
You're too kind.
Protecting the people
is the duty
of Capital Security.
Besides, Jiang Zhan and I
are close friends.
His family is my family.
Zhan is so lucky to have
a friend like you.
I'm also lucky to have
a friend like him.
It's fine. There's no redness.
Let me blow it for you.
From now on,
I'll leave those two in your care.
Don't worry.
With me here,
they'll have food to eat.
Miss Si,
actually,
I've always wanted to give you
this painting.
What's this?
Since you asked,
I'll tell you honestly.
The reason why I saved your sister
is for righteousness
and to repay kindness.
To repay kindness?
A life-saving kindness.
Your mother, Su Ke,
once saved my life.
My mother?
My parents died when I was young.
Before they passed,
they entrusted me to Caiyun Troupe.
When I was just past my coming-of-age,
they bullied me for being young
and alone.
I couldn't fight back,
but I didn't want
to yield to them,
so, in a fit of anger,
I ran away from the troupe.
But I didn't expect
to meet a human trafficker on the way
and almost got beaten to death.
Fortunately,
I was saved by Su Ke.
- Help me!
- You can't escape!
(Su Ke, Jiang Si's mother)
Help me!
Mr. Cui.
- Get lost.
- Yes.
Miss,
are you alright?
Miss?
- Miss?
The year Su Ke took me in
was the happiest time of my life.
Su was a lady
but she took in an actress.
Many people were gossiping about it.
Her father wanted to send me away,
but Su said
that they could gossip if they wanted,
and we shouldn't care.
Even if she sent me away,
they still wouldn't stop.
Though Su didn't care,
I didn't want to trouble her,
so I returned to Caiyun Troupe.
But her words
really enlightened me.
After that,
I no longer let rumors
affect me.
I promised her
that when I returned,
I would perform
the most beautiful dance for her.
Thank you,
Ms. Fei,
for telling me so much.
I lost my mother
right after I was born,
and I have
never met her.
All these years,
I've only been able to picture her
from others'
fragments of words.
Ms. Fei,
I envy you
for how you got to spend
so much time with her.
The world is vast. We'll meet again.
(Fenglin Inn)
Yan, slow down.
Be careful.
You go ahead and leave first.
Yes.
Mr. Yu.
I have something I don't understand.
Before we leave,
I want to ask you.
Go ahead.
The person observing
in the woods that day was you, right?
You must've made a mistake.
That day, I was on patrol elsewhere
and only rushed over
when I heard the startled horse.
You said I risked my life to save them,
but you did the same thing.
(Border of Ling'an)
(Earl Dongping's Mansion)
Greetings, Grandmother.
Yan,
kowtow to your great-grandmother.
Si,
you really have grown bold.
Now, is the family
under your control?
This is serious,
but you didn't even inform
your father and brother.
How can you
bring them back
without telling anyone?
Grandmother, it was my decision.
Si just couldn't bear to refuse me.
Alright, don't speak for her.
I know both of your tempers.
Mother,
this must be handled swiftly.
Yi has suffered greatly.
That Si saved Yi
from danger
is what matters.
It's understandable
that she didn't have time to tell us.
Both of you
are home now.
Si's engagement was canceled,
and Yi got a divorce.
What misdeeds have we done?
Grandmother,
it was Ji and Zhu
who had done misdeeds,
not Yi and Si.
I will uphold our family,
and no one will bully our girls again.
Yan, come on. Get up.
Go greet your great-grandmother.
Go on.
Great-grandmother.
Let me hold your hands, okay?
Yi, get up.
Please have two little red fruits,
one in each hand.
Hold them carefully.
Go on.
You have your happy lives to live.
From now on,
I won't interfere with your matters.
(Morning Drizzle)
(Haitang Chamber)
(The past is
like autumn leaves falling.)
(There's still enough time
to resolve every difficulty.)
You're lying to me, right?
Why would the Grand Princess
kill Yu Qi?
She's got what she wants.
Why would I lie to you?
Dazhou couldn't conquer Nanwu
and recently suffered a defeat.
The Grand Princess blamed everything
on Chiyu Cavalry
and beheaded
their leader, Yu Qi.
- Junior.
- How could this be?
How could this be?
Our people have been
at A Goose to Return for so long.
The news can't be wrong.
Yu Qi is really dead.
Mentor, the Grand Princess
and her daughter
killed my family and my husband.
I want to join you
in attacking Changle Palace.
I'll kill them
to avenge my family
and husband.
Jiang Si.
You're not dead.
You're the Saintess of Nanwu.
I'm not the Saintess of Nanwu.
I'm here for revenge.
The entire court
is under my command
and won't tolerate your insolence.
Then today,
we'll see whether it's your command
or my sword that decides this.
This
is for my family.
You and your daughter Cui Mingyue
have killed innocents.
My father, brother, and sister
all suffered and died because of you.
Today,
I will avenge them.
This
is for my husband,
Yu Qi.
Why did you have to kill him too?
Do you think
he was just the Yu Qi you knew?
Even if I die,
your life will never change.
Shut up!
I was born and raised
in Dazhou,
but you and your daughter
wanted to wipe me out,
leaving me no place in Dazhou.
This
is for myself.
I finally had my revenge.
(Now, )
(Zhan, Father, )
(and Yi)
(are safe and sound.)
(Maybe I'm no longer a jinx, )
(and Yu Qi will be safe too.)
(The End of Episode 19)
(Should I miss him again?)
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
♪ I dare to love and hate ♪
♪ Ask the day and the night ♪
♪ If they saw a glimmer fall and take root ♪
♪ Growing between us ♪
♪ And breeding love ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ And stars ♪
♪ Don't ask what our fate is ♪
♪ Let life carve the growth rings ♪
♪ We'll reach the end eventually ♪
♪ All will bloom in spring ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ We travel at night in the cold ♪
♪ The moonlight shines like water ♪
♪ Those in love will have sweet dreams ♪
♪ Cherish each other in the future ♪
♪ Time goes by, but memories remain ♪
♪ Take a look to remember everything ♪
♪ We will see flowers fill the city again ♪